# **Azat Mingazov**

in azat\_mingazov

zovminga

# About

Analyst with 3 years of experience in digital innovations analysis in oil&gas majors. I'm ready for opportunities in the data analysis field and work with digital products and services in fintech, pharma, e-commerce, energy etc. I have competencies in Python (pandas, numpy, scipy, seaborn), SQL (PostgreSQL, MS SQL, Clickhouse), visualization in Tableau and Power BI, and have knowledge in A/B testing and statistics. I had experience of doing RFM and cohort analysis, and know key product metrics.

Leading roles in more than four R&D projects, mentoring and management of people, problem-solving and deadlines estimating skills.

# **Employment History**

# Middle digital innovations analyst | Strategy analyst

Gazprom Neft, upstream

February 2022 — present time

- developed internal business product technological radar of using digital technologies in business (python, MS Excel, Tableau, Qlik Sense)
- key contributor in creating an internal database of digital solutions providers (using technology maturity metrics)
- provided ad-hoc analytical reports for the deputy COO (more than 10)
- took part in the launch and conversion of 3+ R&D projects with a total potential effect of 40+ m rubles
- created a roadmap and developed digital transformation strategy within ESG agenda in the Construction Department (two projects started)
- did market research and business effects estimation in gas detection UAV development project
- led the effort of digital technologies trend research and benchmarking for the Department of Geological Exploration
- provided direction for 2 junior business analysts and led a team of up to 4 people on R&D projects

#### Junior business analyst

Gazprom Neft

October 2020 — February 2022

- took part on the R&D project of developing a digital twin of a fracturing polygon: conducted 10+ problematic interviews, analyzed potential partners on the market, developed the project conversion plan
- participation in the project of BI system development for well construction parameters control: conducted 15+ problematic interviews and market research, participated in the creation of high-level functional specifications, created the project roadmap
- realized business processes analysis in R&D projects, generated proposals of digital initiatives, prioritization of their implementation
- led assessment of the maturity and readiness of the digital solutions for implementation in upstream business blocks

#### Junior geologist

JV Rosneft and ExxonMobil, Department of Geological Exploration on the Artic Shelf October 2018 — June 2020

#### Education

Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU)1

MS in Geology (First Class), Petroleum Geology BS in Geology, Petroleum Geology

September 2018 — June 2020 September 2014 — June 2018

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup> #21 in the world Top Universities ranking for Natural Science

# X Skills

- Python programming (pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, scipy), SQL (PostgreSQL, Clickhouse, MS SQL)
- A/B testing, product metrics analysis, Data Visualization (Tableau, Power BI)
- Learning data engineering, machine learning and ETL

#### Additional education and certificates

#### **Data Analysis, Karpov Courses**

2022

### Prospect Evaluation in Oil & Gas Exploration, TotalEnergies

February 2019

# Integrated interpretation of seismic data using Petrel 11, Schlumberger

October 2018

# Pet projects

## E-learning analysis pet project

Analysis of data on completed courses and subjects of the training e-learning program (the easiest/hardest courses, RFM analysis etc.) — python (pandas, numpy, seaborn) — <u>github link</u>

#### · Bonus distribution dashboard

Creating dashboard for the HR department which represents employee's performance rating, satisfaction, bonus and other HR metrics distribution — Tableau (using row-level, quick-table calculations) — <u>tableau public link</u>